Guide to the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics Records
University of Houston Libraries
College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics Records
1940-2009
2009-012
University of Houston. College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics
4.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
These records contain 4 boxes and 1 oversize folder relating to the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant.
Historical Note:
The College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics (NSM) is a fairly new college in its current state, but it has a long tradition at the university. In the early days of the university, the components of NSM were part of the College of Arts and Sciences. In the 1970s, this college was divided into the College of Humanities, Fine Arts, and Communication (HFAC), the College of Social Sciences (SOS), and the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics (NSM).
More recently, the College has built a strong reputation in health care and energy research. [1]
References:
[1] Dean's Message. http://nsm.uh.edu/about/msg-dean/ accessed December 5, 2016
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
These records contain 4 boxes and 1 oversize folder relating to the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant. Material includes correspondence, course information, event programs and flyers, program guides, publications, newsletters and faculty reports. This collection is arranged alphabetically by department title and chronologically as necessary. Within each department, material is arranged by the following categories: General Information, Guides, Newsletters, Publications, and/or Reports. Materials range in date from the 1940s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- Biology and Biochemistry
  - General Information by date
    - 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1980s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 2000s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Biology flyer, undated (Drawer F.9, Ovs folder 8)
  - Publications
    - NSF-SST Population Biology, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Chemistry
  - General Information by date
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
    - 1980s (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
    - 1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 2000s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Publications
    - Publications & Activities of the Faculty, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Research Interests of the Faculty, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - First Year Final Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Southwest Regional ACS Meeting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Computer Science
  - General Information by date
    - undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1960s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1970s (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1990s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 2000s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publications
    - Consideration in the Design of an XDS Sigma 7 Multics, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Touchstone Teleprocessing on the Interdata 4, January 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - System-State Model theory and implementation, October 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - OSSL, A user’s guide, November 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - A Universal Translator for Microprocessors, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Energy
  - Newsletters
    - ENERGY, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Energy Laboratory (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Solar Update (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Publications
    - The International Petroleum Supply Situation, March 15-16, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Energy Foundation of Texas, Annual Report, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Proceedings of the 1978 DOE Workshop, March 27-30, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Plain Writing in Texas State Agencies, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Geosciences
  - General Information by date
    - 1940s (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1950s (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1960s (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1970s (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1980s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Guides
    - Geology, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Geology, May 3, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Geology, Dec 11, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Geology, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Geology, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters
    - Alumni (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Geoloy department (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Geosciences Alumni (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Publications
    - Earth Science Career Symposium for Counselors, April 29, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - A Proposal to establish a Doctoral Program, November 5, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Program for the Master of Science in Applied Geophysics, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Applied Geophysics for Geologists, Annual Short Course, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Exploration Geology for Geophysicists, Ann. Short Course, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Proposal for Ph. D program in Geology, July 1, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Instruction and Degree programs in Geophysics, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Pluvial History of Panamint Valley, California, November 11, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Mathematics
  - General Information by date
    - undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1950s (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1960s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1970s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1980s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1990s (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 2000s (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - Lattice Theory Conference, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Reports
    - J.A. Quirein, Divergence Some Nece. Condit. For an Extremum, November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - J.A. Quirein, Suff. Stat. for Divergence & Prob. Of Misclass., December 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Henry P. Decell Jr., HYMPS Numer. Tech. #2, May 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Henry P. Decell Jr. Diff. Corr. Schemes in Nonlin. Reg #3, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - J.A. Quirein, Divergence Considerations I #5, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - M.R. Roberts, Pattern Recogn. & Potent. Function #6, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Terry Wilson, The Concept of Fuzzy Sets in Pattern Recogn #7, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - L.H. Finch, Pattern Recogn. & Linear Discrim. Function #8, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - M.J. O’Malley, Linear Prog. & it’s Application to Patt. Recogn. #9, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dr. Betty J. Barr, Clustering Seeking Technq. In Pattern Recogn. #10, June 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - John Jurgensen, An Evaluating of an Algorithm #11, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - J.A. Quirein, Suff., Stati. For Diverg. & Brattacharyya #13, April 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - W.L. Morris, SYMAT, Covar-Test #17, October 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Jose Oscar Barrios #18, September 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mary Ann Roberts, Computational Forms #19, November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - James Leroy Hall, Perturbation & Sensitivity #20, March 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Henry P. Decell Jr., Rank-K Maximal Stat #21, November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Henty P. Decell Jr., Equivalence Classes of Const. Divergence #23, November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Henry P. Decell Jr., An Expressed for the transformed Covariance #24, March 1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - D.R. Brown, Commutative Semi-groups of real & complex matrices #25, April 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - D.R. Brown, Commutative Semi-groups of real & complex matrices #26, March 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Mary Ann Roberts, Divergence and household transformation #27, November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - L.F. Guseman Jr., The Diff. of the Prob. Of Misclass #28, August 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - J.A. Quirein, Partial Derivatives for Various Scaler func. Of Matrices #29, July 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - B. Charles Peters, On differentiating the probability of error #30, February 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - B. Charles Peters, On differentiating the probability of error II #31, March 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - B.C. Peters Jr., Results on the two population feature selection prob. #32, May 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Rebecca Teun, An Addendum to “A User’s guide #33, July 1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Rebecca Teun & Ken Baker, July 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Homer F. Walker, Some Qualitative remarks on the violation #34, August 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Jack Bryant, Prog. Document., OCM HISTOG PRINTUM #35, August 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Salma Marani, Routine to find maximum average divergence #36, September 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Phillip W. Smith, A simplified package for calculating with splines #37, October 1974 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - H.P. Decell Jr., & W.G. Smiley III, Householder Transformation #38, June 1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - H.P. Decell Jr., & Mike Mayekar, On the Variational Equations #39, March 1975 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Dennison R. Brown, Matthew J. O’Malley, Some results on the Div. #40, November 1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Dennison R. Brown, & Matthew J. O’Malley, A counter-ex. #41, March 1975 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Homer F. Walker, Max. Likelihood Sign. Estimation #42, May 1975 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - B. Charles Peters Jr., An Iterative procedure for obtaining max. #43, July 1975 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Homer f. Walker, On the Numerical Evaluation of the max #44, July 1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Joseph S. Morrell, Appl. Of matrix derivatives to optimization #45, August 1975 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - B. Charles Peters Jr., Addendum to an Iterative Proced #47, September 1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Dennison R. Brown & Matthew T. O’Malley, Some results on Contr. #49, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Natural Sciences and Math
  - General Information by date
    - undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - 1970s (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - 1980s (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - 1990s (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - 2000s (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Stationery (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Newsletters
    - Horoscope (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - In the know (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Momentum (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - News Scanner Monthly (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Update (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Physics
  - General Information by date
    - undated (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
    - 1950s (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - 1960s (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - 1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1990s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2000s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Publications
    - Manned Functions in Space Observations Astronomy, April 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Gregory M. Haas, Large-scale Utilization of Solar Energy, July 11, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Manned Functions in Space observations: Plasmas, Particles, & Fields, November 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Manned Functions in Space observations: Materials Science & Proc., April 23, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - A study of the operation of selected National Research Facilities, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Publications
  - Quest for Excellence Award Gala, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nat. Sci. Foundation Summer Science Training Program, August 23-24, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - C.J. Huang, Concepts & syst. Design of a space emergency re-entry veh., August, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - A. Zlatkis, D.C. Fenimore, Contin. Monitor for chemical protect. Dev., December 10, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MER for petroleum reservoirs in the outer continential shelf, January 29, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Project THEMIS informational processing systems annual report, March 10, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Program & Abstracts, Expochem ‘79, October 22-25, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Program & Abstracts, December 3-6, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Weather Data, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - IPL Program Abstracts, December 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - EIH, Summer 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Lunar Receiving Laboratory, Nat. Aeronautics & Space Admin., October 25, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Abstracts, TCSUH, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Y-Annual Report, ISSO, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Alliance for Nanohealth Press Conference, August 18, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 24)